So now we are going to go through the code of our final example.
And we are using the same sketch as before.
So this is the same sketch which we used in our earlier example.
So I'm not going to go through this sketch again, but you can use the same sketch.
The only difference is the code.
So we will go through the code.
So over here you can see the code in Arduino IDE.
So we are including the libraries first.
Let's just also include the line numbers.
So you can go and file preferences.
And over here you can tick display line numbers.
So it will display the line numbers.
So it will make you easy to understand the code.
Or to program the code as well.
So first we are including the libraries as before.
We are using the same libraries, so we are using libraries which are adafruit libraries, and we are
also including the MFC 5222 module library.
And over here we are initializing the the Led and our MFC 552 module and we are also creating few string
variables which we will use in our example.
Right now we are also initializing the buzzer over here and in setup function we are initializing the
serial communication, right?
So you can see all the data in the serial monitor as well.
Right.
Let me place a card on.
Our module so you can get the data on serial monitor as well.
So as you can see, all the data which we are getting in our LCD, we can also see that data on on our
serial monitor as well.
And we are also able to see the complete sector.
In serial monitor, Right.
So it helps us debug the code and it also helps us understanding the code as well.
So this is why I'm also displaying all the data in serial monitor as well.
So it will help you a lot.
So over here we initializing the serial monitor and then we are initializing the screen and we are printing
RF ID log at the beginning or at the initialization time.
And then we are defining the key.
So to define the key, we have to define key in a byte format.
So we have to start with zero and till five.
So altogether six bytes and this is key A as I have also mentioned in the comment.
So we are defining key A first and we are just using key A so there is no point to define key B, we
are initializing and we are authenticating all the blocks or all the sectors using key A.
Then we are initializing the buzzer as before.
Then we are printing some comments on serial monitor.
After that there is a main loop function in main loop function.
First, we are checking if any card is present on the module or not.
If card is present, then we are checking the card over here.
Then there is a function get which is getting the Uid of the card and we are checking that Uid against
our variable which we have defined over here.
Right?
So if they are not equal then we are clearing out the ID log data and we are clearing out the Uid from
the screen.
So clear data function is used to clear the screen, basically all the data on the screen, right?
So there are three main functions, or you can say two main functions, clear data and print data.
So clear data is to print the sorry cleared the data on the screen and print data is used to print the
data on the screen, the which you are using.
And then there is a get function.
Get function is quite similar as before, so it's just using the same code.
The only difference over here is that we have now using the same code in function format, right?
So we are using the same code is the same loop code which we use before and we are just displaying the
Uid.
Right.
Then there is some data and we are checking the data and printing the data on serial monitor.
As I have shown you before and after that, we are checking the compatibility of card.
So right now this code will only work on Mifare Classic one, K4K and Mayfair mini cards.
Right.
So over here I'm checking PC type.
So this is to check the type of card, what card has been placed on the module.
So if some other card is placed other than mifare classic 1K4K or mini, it will display this message
on the serial monitor.
Then there is our actual code.
Right.
So we have programmed our Mifare classic cards using sector nine, right?
For this particular example, we have used sector nine of classic cards and block 3637 and sector trailer
block, which is 39.
So we are using only sector nine in this example.
So first you have to program your Mifare classic card using our previous examples.
As I have shown you in our earlier videos, how to program classic cards So you have to program mifare
classic cards on Sector nine and you have to use block 36 and 37.
And for sector trailer.
We have defined this key on our card.
So we are using the same key key over here as well to authenticate the cards.
So over here we have defined all the byte variables.
So we are using sector nine, name block, position, block and trailer block.
These are the variables which we are using.
So 36 is a name block 37 is the position block and 39 is a sector trailer block.
So this is our data.
And then we are also defining buffer variable and we are also checking the size of our buffer.
After that, we are authenticating using key A, so we are printing, authenticating, using serial
A on serial monitor.
Then we are checking the status code of card.
Then we are.
Then over here in authentication we are using the authentication key.
A function.
And we are also passing sector trailer block, which is 39.
And you can check it on the structure of memory as well, which I have also provided in the resources
file.
So we are using Sector nine.
Over here you can see Sector nine and Sector nine.
The sector trailer block of sector nine is on 39.
That's why we are using 39 over here, the sector trailer block.
Then we are passing the key, which we have defined in our setup function as before and after that we
are passing the Uid.
Then over here we are checking the status and we are comparing the status.
Okay.
If it's not equal to okay, then we are printing the authentication field error on serial monitor and
we are clearing out all the data from our LCD and we are printing invalid only on our.
And then there is also beep the buzzer sound.
As if the code is equal to the status.
Okay.
Over here, you can see.
Then we are also clearing out the previous data.
And we are also clearing out the invalid data which we printed.
And then we are also beeping the buzzer.
Then we are printing the current sector, which I have shown you in the monitor.
Right.
So this is how we are validating the card.
After validation.
We are reading data from the blog and printing the data on our lead.
So over here you can see read data from the blog and we are printing comments on our monitor.
Right.
So we are using a name block first to print the name.
So in 36, block 36, we have stored names in our classic cards, right?
So over here you can see.
We are first checking the status and we are reading, we are using read function and we are passing
the block number buffer and the buffer size.
Right.
So it will display okay status or it will throw an error If the status is not equal to okay, we will
print a read field and we will also print the error code.
Otherwise if the status is okay.
Then we are printing the buffer data using over here.
You can see them byte error function on our serial monitor.
So it will dump the data on serial monitor.
Right after that, we are printing the same data using using dump byte array string function and this
will print the data on our.
So this is the function.
It's quite simple function.
We are just converting the hex values.
In characters.
So it will get all the hex values from our card.
And then we are just converting those hex values and we are just getting the string value out of hex
and we are just printing the name.
Similarly, the same code is used for position, block and position block.
We are using block 37.
So it will use the same code, the same code, and it will display the position as well.
After there is a halt function to stop reading the data from the card.
So this is the code of our final example.
I have provided this code in the resources file and I have also mentioned the comments in the code file,
so it will help you understand code more easily.